# Rupin Dalvi

#### **SUMMARY**

Experienced in signal and image data analysis. 8+ years experience in MATLAB with proficiency in Python and R. Good command over machine learning libraries such as scikit-learn and TensorFlow as well as big data frameworks like pySpark. Keen to further develop data science skills and apply them in a variety of quantitative disciplines.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **University Health Network, Toronto (2015 – Present)**

Research Analyst II

- Development and testing of a prototype device (software+hardware) to analyse AF data in the catheter lab in order to guide and improve AF ablation procedures.
- Analysis of large cardiac signal and image data in order to detect and diagnose various cardiac disorders, particularly atrial fibrillation (AF).

# University Health Network (2011 - 2015)

Research Analyst I

 Analysis of large cardiac signal and image data in order to detect and diagnose various cardiac disorders, particularly atrial fibrillation (AF).

## Cerebral Diagnostics Canada Inc., Toronto (2010 - 2011)

Brain Imaging Research Analyst/ Signal Analyst

• Development and testing of software designed to provide realtime 3D cortical activity imaging based on EEG signal data.

# **EDUCATION**

# Machine Learning Engineer NanoDegree (2019)

Udacity

## Certificate in Mathematical Finance & Data Science (Estimated Graduation: May 2018)

Lantern Institute, Toronto, Canada

# **Deep Learning Foundations (2017)**

Udacity

# M.A.Sc. in Electrical and Computer Engineering (2009)

The University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

# M.Sc. in Medical Imaging (2005)

University of Surrey, Guildford, Surrey, United Kingdom

# **B.E.** in Electronics Engineering (2003)

University of Mumbai (Bombay), Mumbai (Bombay), Maharashtra, India

#### **SKILLS**

Computer Languages: MATLAB/Octave, Python, JavaScript, intermediate SQL, basic C++ Numerical & ML Libraries: NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SciKit-Learn, TensorFlow, Keras

Big Data: pySpark

**Applications:** Word, Excel, Power Point **Operating Systems:** Windows, Linux

Languages: English (fluent), Marathi (native), Hindi (native)

#### **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS**

- R. Dalvi, I. Hacihaliloglu, R. Abugharbieh. "Fast and Accurate 3D Ultrasound Volume Stitching Using Phase Symmetry and Harris Corner Detection for Orthopedic Applications". SPIE Medical Imaging (MI), San Diego-USA, 2010
- R.Dalvi, A.Suszko, V.S.Chauhan. "Graph Search Based Detection of Periodic Activations in Complex Periodic Signals: Application in Atrial Fibrillation Electrograms". Canadian Conference on Electrical and Computer Engineering (CCECE), Halifax-Canada, 2015
- R.Dalvi, A. Suszko, V.S. Chauhan. "Identification and Annotation of Multiple Periodic Pulse Trains Using Dominant Frequency and Graph Search: Applications in Atrial Fibrillation Rotor Detection". International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC), Orlando, USA, 2016
- S. Gizurarson, **R. Dalvi**, M. Das, A. C.T. Ha, A. Suszko, V. S. Chauhan, Hierarchical Schema for Identifying Focal Electrical Sources During Human Atrial Fibrillation, JACC: Clinical Electrophysiology, November 2016
- S. Kochhäuser, A. Verma, R. **Dalvi**, A.M. Suszko, P. Alipour, P. Sanders, J. Champagne, L. Macle, G.M. Nair, H. Calkins, D.J. Wilber, and V.S. Chauhan., <u>Spatial Relationships of Complex Fractionated Atrial Electrograms and Continuous Electrical Activity to Focal Electrical Sources: Implications for Substrate Ablation in <u>Human Atrial Fibrillation</u> JACC Clinical Electrophysiology, August 2017 [Epub ahead of print].</u>
- S. Nayyar, A.M. Suszko, A. Porta-Sanchez, **R. Dalvi**, and V.S. Chauhan, Long-term cardiac resynchronization therapy reduces T-wave alternans in patients with cardiomyopathy. American Journal of Physiology-Heart and Circulatory Physiology, Under Review

### **PATENTS**

CA2942904A1: System And Method For Focal Source Identification, Inventor(s): Vijay S. Chauhan, Sigfus Gizurarson, **Rupin Haily Dalvi**, Current Assignee: University Health Network (Priority date: 2014-03-31)

#### **REFERENCES**

References available upon request.